# Josh Woodcock // Full Stack Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w00 // www.j0w0.com // www.linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

**Full Stack Software Engineer** that enjoys finding creative solutions to complex problems by utilizing front- and backend technologies. I enjoy engineering the process just as much as writing the code behind it. While I'm able to be analytical and get into the finer details, my design experience enables me to think more creatively and bring a unique perspective to the team.

**Skills:** HTML, CSS / SCSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Amazon AWS, Heroku, Google OAuth, Passport.js, Google Maps API, AJAX, JSON, Websockets, Bootstrap, jQuery, Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, GitHub, Homebrew, npm, RESTful APIs, Git, Stripe, Twilio, WooCommerce, Photoshop, Illustrator.

# **Employment History**

# Front-End / UX Developer

Remedy | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined and redeveloped web app for urgent care bookings that saw an increase of appointment bookings by
  over 1000%. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily
  managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the booking / scheduling process.

# **MIS Web Developer**

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Developed a complete overhaul of the company's corporate WordPress theme and content management system.
- Created and managed marketing event web applications for event registration, check in, lead tracking, and payments.
- Developed business software and helped maintain the company's Intranet on WordPress.

## **Contract Web Developer**

COMNIO | July 2016-May 2017 | Austin, Texas

- Designed and developed online registration and retail contest forms for clients using WordPress.
- Initiated and outlined the company's client portal that integrated with third-party marketing / automation services.

#### **Digital Media Marketing Coordinator**

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

- Maintained corporate website, event landing pages, staff Intranet, and oversaw all email campaigns.
- Planned / developed web applications and business software to assist sales and marketing.

#### **Education**

# **General Assembly: Software Engineering Immersive**

Full Stack, Software Engineering Immersive | Austin, Texas (Remote) | July 2020-October 2020

## **Texas State University**

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas | May 2014

### **Queens College**

National Student Exchange, Graphic Design | Flushing, New York | 2012–2013